<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="790" moduleid="4488" modulename="page" contextid="5894">
  <page id="790">
    <name>Topic 1.1: Understanding pre-apprenticeships</name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 1.8rem;"&gt;Overview&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://lincs-moodle-dev.civicactions.net/mod/glossary/showentry.php?eid=420"&gt;Apprenticeships&lt;/a&gt; expand career opportunities, but many adults face barriers to accessing them. Pre-apprenticeships break down these barriers by supporting adults to prepare for and succeed in apprenticeships and other industry roles. Pre-apprenticeship programs open up critical pathways into rewarding careers — driving greater and more diverse participation in apprenticeships and the broader workforce. These programs also benefit employers by providing screened, well-trained employees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pre-apprenticeship programs can be delivered full time or part time. Some are designed to mimic a typical workday, and others are scheduled to accommodate participants’ other commitments. These p&lt;a&gt;rograms&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;are typically taught in person, but some use blended or online models. Pre-apprenticeships often have partnerships with a range of industry employers, but a relationship with an apprenticeship program is what distinguishes them from other adult education or workforce readiness programs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pre-apprenticeship programs offer career exposure, skill development, job readiness preparation, and holistic supports. High-quality pre-apprenticeships:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Set clear pathways into apprenticeships and other in-demand industry roles,&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Articulate clear entry and success requirements,&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Help participants acquire skills and credentials sought by employers and apprenticeship programs, and&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide support services to remove barriers to participation, including access to resources for transportation, childcare, mental health, and housing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Review the resources listed below to learn more about pre-apprenticeships.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a name="_2lxq0dtr54pm"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a&gt;Recommended reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.apprenticeship.gov/employers/explore-pre-apprenticeship"&gt;What is a pre-apprenticeship program?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(U.S. Department of Labor). The DOL website provides an introduction to pre-apprenticeships — including their benefits and the elements of high-quality programs. Read the case studies to learn more about what pre-apprenticeships can look like across industries and with different participants.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jff.org/resources/jffs-framework-high-quality-pre-apprenticeship-program/"&gt;JFF’s framework for a high-quality pre-apprenticeship program&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Jobs for the Future). This framework outlines six characteristics of high-quality pre-apprenticeships. It is designed to help new or existing programs to improve program quality and equity.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.clasp.org/sites/default/files/publications/2020/04/2020_principleshighqualitypreapprenticeships.pdf"&gt;Principles for a high-quality pre-apprenticeship: a model to advance equity&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(The Center for Law and Social Policy). This report outlines principles for designing high-quality pre-apprenticeships. It identifies similar elements to the JFF Framework identified above but has a deeper focus on how to create equitable, inclusive programs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name="_7d54vpe60gfo"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Recommended viewing&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jff.org/resources/the-essentials-of-a-high-quality-pre-apprenticeship-program/"&gt;The essentials of a high-quality pre-apprenticeship program — webinar recording&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Jobs for the Future). In addition to reading JFF’s framework above, you may also wish to watch this webinar featuring guest speakers from IBM and Pennsylvania’s Apprenticeship and Training Office.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:3:{s:12:"printheading";s:1:"1";s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";s:17:"printlastmodified";s:1:"1";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>5</revision>
    <timemodified>1634323926</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>