<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="781" moduleid="4471" modulename="page" contextid="5877">
  <page id="781">
    <name>Topic 2.1: Identifying and interpreting workforce data </name>
    <intro></intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;p dir="ltr" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Identifying and interpreting workforce data&amp;nbsp;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s important to understand workforce trends, opportunities, and challenges when designing a pre-apprenticeship. This will help ensure your pre-apprenticeship program is leading into an industry with strong demand for more skilled workers. You can use many different sources to learn more about your industry — including workforce data, conversations with staff at your local American Job Center, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a&gt;feedback from apprenticeships and other employers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the following resources to learn more about the different types of workforce data and local workforce systems. You can also use the tools listed below to access secondary data and identify relevant contacts who will be able to share more about your local job market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name="_4aau27qc8usm"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a&gt;Recommended reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.apprenticeship.gov/apprenticeship-industries"&gt;Apprenticeship industries&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(U.S. Department of Labor). The DOL website contains information about in-demand apprenticeships across different industries. Access industry-specific resources, such as fact sheets and case studies.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.urban.org/research/publication/understanding-local-workforce-systems#:~:text=A%20local%20workforce%20system%20encompasses,the%20local%20economy%20over%20time."&gt;Understanding local workforce systems&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Urban Institute). This report provides an overview of how government, industry, education and training providers, and other community organizations can work together to deliver effective workforce services.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a name="_5obpvjmzglw5"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Helpful tools&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bls.gov/regions/home.htm"&gt;Geographic information&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics). This page includes a range of employment data at local, regional, and state levels. To find data for your area, visit the page and select your state.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://lmi.workforcegps.org/resources/2015/04/03/15/48/Guide_to_State_and_Local_Workforce_Data"&gt;Guide to state and local workforce data&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Workforce GPS, sponsored by DOL). This guide provides links to state and local employment and economic data from government and private sector sources.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.careeronestop.org/LocalHelp/AmericanJobCenters/find-american-job-centers.aspx"&gt;American Job Center finder&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Career One Stop, sponsored by DOL). American Job Centers (AJC) help people search for jobs and training as well as answer other employment related questions. There are almost 2,400 AJCs nationwide. Use this tool to find your local AJC.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bls.gov/bls/ofolist.htm"&gt;State labor market information contact list&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(U.S. Bureau of Labor Market Statistics). This site contains the list of each state’s labor market information contact — don’t be afraid to give them a call.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:3:{s:12:"printheading";s:1:"1";s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";s:17:"printlastmodified";s:1:"1";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>6</revision>
    <timemodified>1634568479</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>